# KAY MCKELLY FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

**4** 408.209.5214

Seattle, WA

**y** geekscatv2

in kaymckelly

kaymckelly

Front-end focused full stack web developer with a passion for learning new languages/frameworks and over a decade of teaching experience. Excited about building things with the NEAP (Node, Express, Angular, PostgreSQL) stack, Bootstrap, HTML/CSS, and whatever I learn post.

# **Skills**

#### HTML, CSS

Bootstrap

Pug (formerly Jade)

## **JAVASCRIPT**

Node.js

Express.js

Angular.js

#### DATABASES

PostgreSQL

Knex IOUERY

GIT/GITHUB

## FRONT-END DEVELOPMENT

User Interface Design

Accessibility

Mobile-first Design

PAIR PROGRAMMING

AGILE WORKFLOW

OAUTH

TEST-DRIVEN DEVELOPMENT

OBJECT-ORIENTED PROGRAMMING

# **Experience**

#### Freelance

Full Stack Web Developer

Seattle, WA Aug 2016 to Current

- Work with clients to develop an app or website that is truly a collaborative effort
- Remotely completes work and delivers on or before deadlines
- Self-starter, highly motivated to build what you need

## Galvanize

Full Stack Web Development Fellow

Seattle, WA Feb 2016 to Jul 2016

- Intensive six-month web development immersive program, primarily focused on the NEAP (Node, Express, Angular, PostgreSQL) stack
- Planned and built a variety of fully functional web applications (see Projects section for more information)
- Built and managed PostgreSQL databases
- Performed debugging in development and production
- Used a test-driven development approach in an Agile workflow environment
- Functioned as a valuable team member in both group and pair programming settings

## University of Massachusetts Amherst

#### Teaching Associate

Amherst, MA Sep 2012 to Jun 2014

- Worked as primary course instructor for Social Problems, Sociology of American Culture, Data Collection & Interpretation, and Sociology of Sexualities
- Designed original curriculum suitable for each course
- Managed and taught 20-43 students per semester
- · Facilitated discussions on controversial and sensitive topics
- Mentored students, with a particular focus on those from disadvantaged groups

#### Instructional Media Lab Consultant

Amherst, MA Aug 2010 to Feb 2011

- Supported faculty through workshops, online courses, and one-on-one instruction to better integrate technology into higher education
- Maintained a ticket system for individual troubleshooting and problem solving
- Taught faculty how to optimize their use of a variety of instructional technologies in the classroom
- Encouraged increased usage of technology in higher education
- Tested new educational technologies, including several learning management systems (LMS)

#### **Teaching Assistant**

Amherst, MA Sep 2008 to Dec 2013

- Served as teaching assistant for Criminology, Introduction to Sociology, Race/Class/Gender/Ethnicity, Sociological Theory, and Data Collection & Interpretation
- · Evaluated student assignments and assessments
- · Responded to student concerns and questions
- Maintained database of student evaluations
- · Assisted faculty members with instructional preparation, delivery, and assessment

# **Projects**

#### Boost

- Capstone project for Galvanize Seattle (G21 cohort) that is a demonstration of a full stack app built within a two week period of time
- Provides a space for users to encourage one another within an app focused on self-care
- Built with Angular, CSS, HTML, Bootstrap, databases, oAuth, and Facebook login
- https://github.com/kaymckelly/boost

# Seattle Neighborhood Challenge (SNC)

- Built a full stack app in a team-based Agile workflow environment with five other people
- I acted as project manager, in addition to being a contributing member of the development team
- · Enables users to search for "challenges" (events) happening in a given Seattle neighorhood, RSVP, create, and attend them
- Built with React Native, CSS, oAuth, Facebook login, Google Maps API, databases, Agile workflow, Express, and Knex
- https://github.com/supergroup-g21/snc

## Brows on Fleek

- Front-end focused development project
- Provides users with a way to search for a place to get their eyebrows done near a given location
- Utilizes Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, Google Maps APIs, Agile workflow, DOM manipulation, response to user-initiated events, and linting
- https://github.com/kaymckelly/brows-on-fleek

# **Education**

# University of Massachusetts Amherst

Masters Sociology 2014

Thesis: "Beauty Through Control: Forming Pro-Anorexic Identities in Digital Spaces"

## University of California Santa Cruz

Bachelors Sociology 2008

Honors in the major

# **Volunteering**

# Prison Birth Project · Full Spectrum Doula

Sep 2014 to Nov 2015

The Prison Birth Project provides doulas for women who are incarcerated and pregnant. During my time with this organization, I attended hospital births, advocated for appropriate humane treatment of mothers in accordance with Massachusetts anti-shackling laws, and assisted the women before, during, and after their births.